# **CLAUDINEI BIDO**

Software Engineer

## **CONTACT ME**

+49 179 103 7171 claudinei.bido@gmail.com Berlin, Germany

## SOCIAL

linkedin.com/in/bidoc github.com/bidodev

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) / SASS

React / Redux

Node.js / Express

MongoDB / Mongoose

SQL / MySQL Server

**Technical Support** 

Linux Servers / AWS

Git / GitHub

Firebase

## **OTHERS SKILLS**

Fast Learner

Problem Solving

Team Player / Communication

Hands on / Initiative

Organization

## **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese - Native

English - Full professional proficiency

German - Professional working proficiency

Italian - Professional working proficiency

## HERE'S MY STORY:

I am a Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript/ES6 / Node.js / React / Redux / Express / MongoDB, side experiences on C / C++ / Pascal / Delphi / LUA / SQL / PHP, System Administration, Technical Support, Databases, AWS, Management.

I define myself as a problem solver who loves challenges when there is a problem I will work towards a solution.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Tutor**

## DCI DIGITAL CAREER INSTITUTE GMBH

JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Responsible for helping students learn and reviewing exercises
- Explaining how to solve problems and checking completed work
- Helping students develop study skills and organization techniques

#### Social Media Moderator

## ARVATO - BERTELSMANN / MAJOREL

SEP 2017 - OCT 2019

- Ensuring a quality experience for all users according to the clients terms of service
- Management of online social media platform content
- · Investigate and resolve customer queries

#### **Linux Systems Administrator**

#### SONTAG COMMERCIAL AUTOMATION

FEB 2014 - DEC 2016

- Development of scripts in Shell Script, PHP / Lua in order to automate tasks
- Setup and administration of Servers (LAMP, Node JS). Networks analysis, backups
- Designer and scalability of the hardware and cloud (AWS)

#### **Technical Support Technician**

#### SMO INTERNET PROVIDER

JAN 2012 - NOV 2013

- Customer Service support and miscellaneous product updates
- Setting up and designing servers and clouds (VMWARE) for commercial automation
- Maintenance of hardware, component updates, fault correction

## IT Technician - Internship

#### SENAI - SERVICO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAGEM INDUSTRIAL

MAR 2007 - JAN 2010

- Maintenance of servers and desktops for corporate clients
- Implementation of personal and corporate networks
- Technical Customer Support

### **EDUCATION**

### Full Stack Web Development Course

#### DCI DIGITAL CAREER INSTITUTE GMBH

SET 2019 - JAN 2021

## **Computer Science**

UFFS - UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DA FRONTEIRA SUL

FEB 2010 - JAN 2012

#### IT Computer Technician

SENAI - SERVICO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAGEM INDUSTRIAL

FEB 2007 - JAN 2010